Deinichenko Ivan

Senior Frontend Developer

Location: Belgrade, Serbia

Date of birth: 27.05.1989 (34 years old)

Phone number: +381638096675

E-mail: <u>deathklaat89@gmail.com</u>

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/deinichenko.ivan

Telegram: @frostklaat

Overall experience

I am a passionate and hardworking frontend developer who loves to solve interesting problems, share and gain new experiences, and bring all projects to the best possible state.

I have over 10 years of experience developing SPAs (Vue/Nuxt) and web and mobile games as a frontend/full-stack developer. Experienced with browser APIs, social media APIs, Google APIs (e.g. Firebase), REST, web sockets.

Worked on some Unity 3D projects as a C# developer.

Have experience working with backend, including PHP, MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Yii, Yii2, Codelgniter, Laravel.

I worked part-time as a team lead on a game development team for several years. Wrote technical specifications, solved organizational problems with the team, conducted daily stand-ups, managed tasks in Jira, planned and evaluated projects.

Skills area

- Software development
- Object-oriented architecture and design
- Front-end development
- HTML application/games development
- Unity games development
- Documentation creation
- Cross-browser markup/development
- Third-party widgets integration
- Code quality assurance (tech debt, refactoring, code review)
- Problem solving

Technical domains

Languages	JavaScript ES 5/6+, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, C#, PHP
Frameworks and libraries	VueJS 2/3, Nuxt 2/3, Vuex, Vue Router, Vuetify, Vue Bootstrap, Lodash, jQuery, Phaser, Spine, Axios, TweenJS, ChartJS
Technologies	Social API (e.g. Facebook, VK), Firebase API (remote config, realtime database), Browser APIs
DBMS	MySQL
Tools	Git, Jira, Confluence, Bash, Webpack, NPM, Composer, Yarn, Brew, Docker, Figma, Photoshop, Browsers DevTools
IDEs	VSCode, PhpStorm

Education

2006-2012 - Petrozavodsk State University, Math faculty, Information system and technologies - Specialist (equal to master's degree)

Languages

- Russian Native
- English B2
- Serbian A1

Notable projects

Multiplayer Solitaire Card Game

A game of cards for multiple players. Single elimination tournament. Every round two players battle each other to solve the solitaire game faster. Players also can use boosters to slow down the enemy or get benefits for themselves.

Technologies: HTML 5, Canvas, CSS 3, SASS, JavaScript ES5, jQuery, AJAX, REST API, Webpack, LongPolling.

Responsibility: Complete development of frontend of the project. Optimization and refactoring project for mobile devices. Migration from divs game architecture to canvas (We found that the divs one was slow).

Text and graphic novel game

Mobile game for Play Market and App Store. Users can choose a novel from a list and read it by tapping on the screen. Non-linear storylines depend on the user's choices.

Technologies: VueJS, Vuex, Vuex Persisted State, Vue Router, Vue Draggable, Vuetify, Vue SVG Icon, Vue i18n, Vue Touch Events, ES6+, Axios, SASS, Webpack, npm, git.

Third party libraries e.g. amplitude and yandex metrics.

Codelgniter, Laravel, PHP7, MySQL, Redis.

Responsibility: Complete development of the project. Architecture design, markup, frontend and backend functionality. Database design and implementation. Performance optimization. Integration of third-party plugins such as billing, notifications, localization, metrics. Migration from Codelgniter to Laravel as backend architecture refactoring.

Farm-like game (Hay day for example)

Multiplayer farming simulator where you can plant crops and trees, sell products, raise animals, enhance your farm and city, etc.

Technologies: ES5, ES6, HTML5, Canvas, CSS3, SASS, gulp, Spine (JS), WebSockets, Lodash, jQuery.

Responsibility: Support and update project's functionality, generate new content ideas, create new activities and locations for players. Write quests texts, calculate in-game economy, get feedback from the community, implement new functionality. Collaborate with the design and QA department. Do not forget about KPIs. Performance optimization. Cross-browser support, mobile support.

Work experience

Acronis (Belgrade, Serbia), Nov 2022 - Present

Position: Senior Software Developer

Responsibilities:

Development of the acronis.com frontend part. Tasks estimation, code review, support for old functions, implementation of new functionality, search engine optimization.

Technologies: Figma, HTML, CSS, NuxtJS, VueJS, TypeScript, SEO, 3rd-party integrations, Git

Notable points:

- Migrated several site's big sections from drupal to current Vue JS ecosystem
- Developed a system for generating and customizing site's structured data markup (Search Engine Optimization)
- Top 1 tech debt and todos resolver of the team

Noveo (St. Petersburg, Russia), Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

Position: Middle+ Vue JS Developer

Responsibilities:

Development of frontend side of outsource/outstaff applications, Projects estimation, Code Review.

Technologies: Figma, HTML, CSS, NuxtJS + CompositionAPI, Tailwind CSS, 3rd-party integrations.

Achievements:

- Fixed a lot of bugs
- Made some refactoring and technical improvements for existing components
- Migrated project from Nuxt v2 to Nuxt with Composition API what made development easier and faster
- Migrated components to tailwind css\

Notable project: Car sharing web application. Selection of a car. Vehicle equipment. Selecting the place and time for delivery of the car. Payment service.

Startup Company (St. Petersburg, Russia), May 2021 - Feb 2022

Position: Unity / Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development of visual novels for Play Market and App Store based on Unity3D Engine. Integration of billing, notifications, metrics, social plugins etc. Development of project's administration SPA based on VueJS. **Technologies**: Unity 3D, C#, OOP, SOLID, Logcat, JarResolver. JS ES6+, VueJS, Vuex, Vue Router, Vue Bootstrap, Firebase API.

Startup Company (St. Petersburg, Russia), Jun 2020 - May 2021

Position: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities: Development of text novels for Play Market based on HTML5, VueJS and WebView. Development of project's administration SPA based on VueJS.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES6+, VueJS, Vuex, Vuetify, Vue Router, Vue i18n, Vue Draggable, Vue SVG Icons, Webpack, npm, composer, docker, Laravel, Codelgniter, MySQL, Redis, CI/CD.

Notable points: I took a raw hackathon project and rebuilt it from scratch into a working project with bunch of new features, which was later published on the PlayMarket

Red Panda Labs (St. Petersburg, Russia), Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Position: Unity Developer

Responsibilities: Development of mobile games for Play Market and App Store in hyper-casual genre. Core functionality of games, integration of billing, localization, notifications, ads providers, socials etc.

Technologies: Git, Unity 3D, C#, REST API, OOP, SOLID, Figma, Logcat, XCode. **Notable points**:

- Gained a lot of experience in mobile development using Unity for Android and iOS
- Designed, built from scratch and released several games with mechanics that were completely new to me

Fotostrana.ru (St. Petersburg, Russia), Oct 2018 - Sep 2019

Position: Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development and support of HTML 5 canvas games. Match 3, some clickers, arcades, mahjong, puzzles etc. Additionally refactoring and optimization of the platform's legacy.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES6+, WebSockets, Webpack, npm, HTML5 + Canvas, CSS 3, SASS.

Notable points:

- I gained experience working with web sockets
- Created several games that were completely new to my experience
- As part of the technical hours, I gained experience working with web workers, PWA and creating libs and NPM packages
- Re-assembled several games from scratch in the shortest possible time

Fotostrana.ru (St. Petersburg, Russia), Oct 2017 - Oct 2018

Position: Frontend Developer

Responsibilities: Development of new functionality for farm-like games on social platforms. Supports and updates actual functionality, communicates with the community, reruns regular activities, creates the new ones.

Technologies: Git, Javascript ES5, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Gulp, WebSockets, Lodash, Social API, REST API, Photoshop. Partially PHP, Yii 2, MySQL.

Notable points:

- After optimization of the staff, I successfully supported and updated all projects of the gaming department being the only dev in the team
- Improved and systematized the process of creating art for updates with the design team
- Figured it out on my own and took over the backend of the project
- Completely led the main project, taking into account the development of new content and functionality, generation of ideas and concepts, calculation of economics, creation of quests, writing narratives, etc.
- Independently launched several seasonal activities, which allowed the main project to stay within the set KPIs longer.

ACT 222 (Petrozavodsk, Russia), Oct 2012 - Oct 2017

Position: Full Stack Developer, Team Lead

Responsibilities:

As a developer: Development of HTML games. Markup, frontend logic, backend logic, database design.

As a team lead: meet-ups / stand-ups, communication between product owners and development team, Jira tracking, sprints planning, tasks and

project estimates. Consulting, research of new ideas and technologies, takes part in product brainstorms.

Technologies: Git, JavaScript ES5, HTML5, CSS3, Canvas, jQuery, REST API, PHP5, Yii, MySQL, Photoshop, WebSockets/Long Polling, Social networks APIs, Unity 3D (partially, last year).

Notable points:

- Updated project structures and did everything necessary to transfer projects to Git. Added use of Git to workflow. Taught the team how to use Git
- Together with devops, we organized a system for creating an environment for new projects and a system for deploying updates to production
- Took on technical leadership of the team, integrated Scrum and Agile
- Reached all the KPIs
- Created a bunch of small games from scratch
- Took part in a project to convert slots from flash to html5 for a large company from the market as an outsource developer.